manfrotto.com 2018-02-25

# Privacy Policy

### 1 Consumer data Privacy Policy 

This Privacy Policy describes, in accordance with Art. 13 of the Italian Legislative Decree 196/2003 n. 196, “Personal Data Protection Code”, the Information which provides the protection of persons and of other subjects in regard to the processing of personal data. It is a document of a general nature which informs about the criteria of the correct processing of personal data executed on or through the Site and that explains how the personal data we collect from Users when using our websites and the services governed by this Privacy Policy (hereinafter referred to as “ ** _Services_** ”). Additionally, the Information is based on the Recommendation N. 2/2001, relative to the “ **minimum requirements for collecting personal data on-line in the European Union** ” and, in particular, the methods, times and nature of the information that the Data Controller of the processing must provide to the Users when the latter connects to web pages, independently from the purpose of the connection. 

### 2 Data Controller of personal data (art. 28 of the Privacy Code)

The Data Controller is the company Lino Manfrotto + Co. S.p.a., (hereinafter referred to as “ **Manfrotto** ”), and/or the company Vitec Group Italia S.p.A, company incorporated under the laws of Italy. The person responsible for the processing is the pro-tempore Legal Representative.

### 3 Location of data processing

The data is processed at the executive offices of the Data Controller and in any other place in which the involved Parties in the processing are located.

### 4 Times or duration of the processing

Data is processed for the time necessary to perform the service requested by the User, or requested by the objectives set forth herein. The User can always, at any time, request the interruption of the processing or the deletion of the data.

### 5 Terms for the application of the present policy

The following services are subject to this Privacy Policy:

  1. Generating a User Account on the Manfrotto’s site;
  2. Services available through the Manfrotto’s account;
  3. Other “Manfrotto’s” services to which this Privacy Policy is applied

### 6 Types of data collected, purposes and methods of processing

Through the browsing of the Manfrotto’s site, personal interests and information might be acquired. Such information, however, is collected at the only and exclusive purpose of providing the services requested and, possibly, to verify the quality of the services offered. Personal data is collected at the time of the registration and/or of the use of our Services.

  * At the time of registration, in fact, various personal details are requested which are useful for the activation or the continuation of relations with our company. These fields are marked as required. Additional personal details may be voluntarily supplied by the User in order to enable us to offer comprehensive Services, at a higher level of customization. When the Users use their social media as a login ( _Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, Instagram, Vimeo or Google_ )basic information may be retrieved directly from the social media identity, for example to verify the identity of the User, the age bracket and the country of origin.
  * When using our Services, independently from registration, we may collect and process the personal data relative to the use of our Services to improve the overall User’s experience. The User can limit the amount of information collected by setting the preferences relative to the privacy in the Services, by modifying the settings of the device or of the browser or according to the method of use of the Services.

### 7 Objective of the processing:

The data is processed for objectives aimed at the achievement of social goals and, in any case, connected and instrumental to the activities of our company such as for example purposes related to:

* The acquisition of information and the updating of our records, useful for the activation or continuation of relations with our company.
* The implementation of technical, logistics and of other types of activities on our behalf and the implementation of the services supplied by our company.
* The management of orders and the processing of payments.
* The communication with the client ( _relative to the purchases or the change of terms, conditions and policies, offers and promotions, reviews, customer satisfaction_ ).
* The management of the client area; data relative to the position in which we have been expressly authorized according to the settings on the privacy of Manfrotto’s account, of the applications and the browser installed and the devices used. Such information is used to improve the user’s experience and the overall quality of the Services.
* The prevention of fraud and violations to the detriment of our website.

Users are always free to provide personal data for the objectives for which they connected to the Manfrotto’s site.   
However, missing data may in some cases, implicate the impossibility of obtaining what has been requested.

Manfrotto carries out the processing of personal data in the respect of what is strictly necessary for the implementation of the service. The expression “personal data” shall mean “any information concerning an identified or identifiable person such as name, identification number, location data, an on-line personal identification number or one or more elements characteristic of one’s physical, physiological, genetical, economic, cultural or social identity”.   
Moreover, “sensitive data” shall mean “personal data allowing the disclosure of racial or ethnic origin, philosophical, religious or other beliefs, political opinions, membership of political parties, trade unions, associations or organizations of a religious, philosophical, political or trade-unionist character as well as personal data revealing health status and sex life ( _art. 4 of Legislative Decree n.196/2003_ ). Additionally, “judicial data” shall mean personal data disclosing the measures provided for in Section 3, letters from a) to o) and from r) to u) of Presidential Decree n. 313 of November 14th 2002, concerning the criminal record office, the register of offence-related administrative sanctions and the relevant current charges or the status of being either defendant or the subject of the investigation under Articles 60 and 61 of the Criminal Procedure Code.

Manfrotto, therefore, informs that “sensitive” data shall not be handled on its site. 

If the User sends in a request of information personal data and/or of contact of any third party other than its own self, the User acknowledges that said operation involves a handling of personal data for which it establishes itself as an autonomous owner, consequently assuming all the obligations and responsibilities provided by the Privacy Policy. Thus, the User guarantees the Data Controller of the processing that any data of third party subjects indicated by the User and treated as if the third party had supplied its own informed consent to the handling, has been acquired by the User in full compliance with the Privacy Policy. The User indemnifies the Data Controller with respect to any claims, requests of damage reimbursement that may come from any third party due to the provision of the data indicated by the User in breach of the regulation on the protection of personal data.

### 8 Communication and dissemination of data (Art. 13 subparagraph 1, letter d – Legislative Decree 196/2003)

The personal data of the Interested Party, if necessary, may be communicated in Italy and/or abroad to:

* Subjects whose authority to access data is recognized by the applicable law, secondary legislation, European Community legislation as well as collective bargaining.
* Companies part of our Group (www.vitecgroup.com)
* Subjects to whom the communication of personal data may be necessary or, in any case, related to the management of the contractual relationship ( _studies of consultation, studies of work consultation for the elaboration of payroll, Judicial Offices, Chambers of Commerce, Labor Union Centers and Offices, authorities of Public Safety, Health, Inspections, Public Administration, Trade Union Organizations, Airports, Flight Agencies, Customs and insurance companies_ ) with the methods and for the objectives listed hereinbefore.
* Collaborators or employees of Manfrotto, in the scope of the relative tasks and/or any contractual obligations, including the Managers of the processing and the Appointees, appointed pursuant to Legislative Decree 196/2003.
* Our sales network.
* Our distributors, post offices, shippers and couriers for the sending of documentation and/or material.

Third parties which provide support of any type for the provision of services for the group’s companies in relation to whom they execute operations of personal data processing are held by the latter Responsible parties in the processing and are contractually required to respect the security measures and the privacy of the handling. The identity of said third parties is made known to the Users. In some cases, the employees of third party companies which collaborate with Manfrotto, may be assigned to the handling of the data.

With the consent of the interested parties, if required by law, and in any case subject to appropriate information which specifies the various purposes the personal data may be communicated to third party subjects, public or private, unrelated to Manfrotto, which will process it as autonomous Data Controller of the processing, pursuant to the definition listed in Legislative Decree n. 196/03. Our Group is not liable, in any form, for the processing of personal data executed by said third party Data Controllers. 

Furthermore, Manfrotto does not undertake any responsibility for: 

  1. Regulations and methods of the management of personal data on other websites reachable from our pages through links and references. 
  2. The contents of any email services, web hosts and chat forums provided to the Users. 

The processing operations connected to web services offered by this website take place at the headquarters of the company Manfrotto and, possibly, at the headquarters of the external Processors and are overseen by assigned individuals responsible for the management of the services requested, the marketing activities, if requested by the User, and to the activity of data storage and of occasional maintenance operations. 

The specific and expressed consent shall be required if there is the need for communication of data to third parties not expressly indicated. 

Personal data is in no event disseminated, intending with such term to provide their knowledge in any way to a plurality of unspecified subjects. 

Personal data provided by the Interested party, without prejudice to their free circulation to the Countries members of the European Union, may be transferred also to a Country outside to the European 

Union, following prior consent and within the limits laid down in articles 43 and 44 of the Legislative Decree n. 196 of June 30th 2003. 

### 9 Rights of the Interested Party (Art. 7 Legislative Decree 196/2003)

The subjects to whom the data refers, have the right, at any time, to obtain confirmation of the existence or otherwise of the personal data concerning them, to know its content and origin, to verify its accuracy or to request its integration or update, in other words its rectification ( _art. 7 of legislative Decree n. 196/2003_ ).

The interested party has also under the same article the right to request the cancellation or transformation into anonymous form or the blocking of data processed in violation of the law as well as to oppose themselves, for legitimate reasons, to their processing. 

The requests may be addressed informally to the establishment responsible for the processing which is the company Vitec Group Italia Spa by sending communication via email to the address: [privacy@manfrotto.com](mailto:privacy@manfrotto.com)

It should be noted that once eliminated the personal data may not be recovered and also the contents memorized in the Services shall be permanently eliminated. The User’s personal data shall be deleted also when it will no longer be necessary for the objectives for which it was originally collected. 

The data subjects may exercise all the rights set forth in art.7 of L.n.196/2003 (including the rights of data access, updating, objects to data processing and cancellation).

The processor is Vitecgroup Italia spa. Please remember that, according to the Privacy Code under L.D. 196/2003, you can oppose in any moment to the above mentioned data processing by sending an e-mail to the following address: [privacy@manfrotto.com](mailto:privacy@manfrotto.com)

It should be noted that once eliminated the personal data may not be recovered and also the contents memorized in the Services shall be permanently eliminated. The User’s personal data shall be deleted also when it will no longer be necessary for the objectives for which it was originally collected. 

### 10 Web surfing data

On this site, analysis systems are utilized which serve to measure and analyze visits to our website. We use your IP address to collect data about the pages visited on our site, the browser and the computer, the URI ( _Uniform Resource Identifier_ ) notation addresses or the requested resources, the time of request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in reply, the numerical code indicating the status of the response provided by the server ( _successful, error, etc._ ) and other parameters relative to the user’s operating system and the computer environment.

This information is not collected to be associated with identified Interested party but their very nature could, through elaborations and associations with data held by third parties, allow Users to be identified.

Personal data, therefore, is utilized which transmission is implicit in the Internet communication protocols for the sole purpose of obtain anonymous statistical information on the Site usage and to verify its correct functioning.

The data in question could be used to ascertain responsibility in case of any computer violations to the detriment of the Site above. 

The Site uses Google Analytics, a service of web analysis provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"), but the intervention to make the IP anonymous with the tools offered by Google is expected. 

Please see the Cookies Policy for Google Analytics at the following link: [Cookies Policy for Google Analytics](http://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage) and find out more about the method with which Google – third party – uses its users’ data at the link [Google – third party](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)

Google Analytics uses cookies, text files which are stored on the terminal of the interested party to allow statistical analysis in aggregate form.

### 11 Cookie and Tracing

A cookie and similar technologies are small pieces of data used to store on the computer technical and/or personal, identify the Users of a service and enable certain features. Such cookies are used by the Data controller and its partners for technical, statistical and/or profiling purposes. Cookies contain only information which is voluntarily supplied by the Client. Cookies do not identify the User on third party websites, including websites of the analysis suppliers. It is possible to configure the browser so that the accepting of cookies is, according to some criteria, denied or that a notification is received before a cookie is stored. 

For additional information about cookies used by the Services and on how to reject them, visit the [Technical Cookies Policy accessible by clicking here.](https://www.manfrotto.co.uk/site-terms/cookies-policy)

### 12 Commitment of the User

To protect the privacy of the very young people is very important. Manfrotto does not address its Services to children, although they are usually suitable even to minors. Manfrotto encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with children and to support them while surfing the Internet. 

By registering to one of the Services and the acceptance of this Privacy Policy, the User confirms to have the age required in his/her country to subscribe a contract. Additionally, the Users confirms to have previously obtained the parents/guardians consent required in the Country of residence, where applicable. Manfrotto reserves the right to contact the User to verify the possession of said requirements and, in the absence of the above, the right to suspend or completely eliminate the account if the User does not have the proper requirements.

The User guarantees the quality of the information supplied for the Services. All personal data submitted to Manfrotto must be true, correct and up to date. The User assumes full responsibility that the information provided is in conformity with this principle. Additionally, the User guarantees to have obtained the explicit consent from all those who own rights of personal image, intellectual property or of other type on the contents in question and to have been authorized to load them and save them in the Services.

### 13 Modifications to the Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy will be updated by Manfrotto so that Users are promptly informed of these changes on the processing of their data. The User, through any mean of communication available, shall be informed about important changes relative to the Privacy Policy. Consequently, please check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification shown at the bottom. In the event of rejection of the changes made to this Privacy Policy, the User must cease to use this Application and may request the Data Controller to have his/her Personal Data removed. Unless otherwise specified, the previous Privacy Policy will continue to be applicable to Personal Data collected up to that time. 

Date of the latest update: March 6th 2017
